Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
The Earth Federation's Third Fleet...
...staged an attack on
the space fortress, Solomon...
...and broke into it using
their new weapon, the Solar System.
Big Zam's Last Stand
I botched it. I can't believe
I could have been so careless.
Sleggar's G-Fighter is returning to the ship.
It looks like the left engine has been hit.
Sleggar! Do you copy?! Come in!
I read you.
Landing on Deck 3.
Something wrong, Ensign?
It's nothing.
Not enough missiles from starboard!
Don't slack off.
Fraw Bow, bring Chief Vammas
up from the sub-bridge.
Ensign Mirai.
Private conversations are prohibited
during battle... but don't shut me out, Mirai.
I'd like to think that I'm
capable enough to watch over you.
Bright...
I understand how you feel...
...but I'll always be here waiting for you.
Yes, sir?
Ensign Mirai isn't feeling well.
Take over her position for the time being.
Yes, sir!
I'll relieve you now.
Bright...
Anti-aircraft guns!
Object approaching portside! Got that?!
Get a move on!
Deal with the left engine when the fire's out!
Howard!
You gotta replace the busted armor panels.
And the fuel pump to engine no. 2.
I'm pretty sure there's a leak.
Okay. I'll get on it.
And fill it up with fuel and ammo.
Make it fast.
Please give us 15 minutes.
You've got 10.
I've gotta get re-fuelled myself.
Hurry up!
We've got 10 minutes to fix it!
Howard!
Where's Lieutenant Sleggar?!
He was headed toward the waiting box.
Okay. Thanks.
Lieutenant! You're not injured.
Ensign. What are you doing
in a place like this?
Well?
I'm so glad...
Ensign. Enough of that.
Don't be foolish.
Lieutenant Sleggar. All prepared for takeoff!
On my way!
See you later.
Lieutenant...!
Please don't die.
Ensign Mirai... When you're young,
things can be very chaotic.
You shouldn't take your own feelings
too seriously at the moment.
What's that supposed to mean?
Hm...? Well... it doesn't matter.
Lieutenant...
Ensign, I'm not the kind of man
who deserves your affection.
No, Sleggar...
To me, you're...
You dazzle me, Ensign.
We're worlds apart.
But...
This is just a cheap ring...
but it's a memento of my mom.
I'd hate to lose it in space.
Hold onto it for me.
Thank you.
Look after that ring, Ensign!
Lieutenant...
At Granada, Kycilia's base to the south
of the moon's Ural Mountains...
...a fleet was preparing to take off
in an attempt to rescue Solomon.
The fleet had been swiftly assembled
under the command of M'Quve.
Not bad... There are a lot of
enemy forces left inside the base.
Why you...!
Be careful! There's a new weapon! It's huge!
What?! How many are there?!
Wait. It seems there's only one new model.
The rest are just Rick Doms and Zakus.
Let's get 'em!
No! Hang on!
We don't know their strength.
Those measly pawns are coming this way.
Show them how the Big Zam differs from
any other mobile armor or mobile suit!
Yes!
If you're gonna come out, come out already!
My beams...!
It's a monster!!
A monster?
I'll check it out!
This is the control room!
Your Excellency!
What is it?!
Where are you, Your Excellency?!
I'll fight in the Big Zam!
So many enemy mobile suits have entered.
But our remaining fleets
are about to take off!
There's no need for you to fight in person!
You're wrong.
We've reached the point where
we must use all our fighting strength!
Zenna...
Mineva...
I hope you've escaped to safety.
It's an escape rocket. One of ours.
Its course?
It appears to have been launched
from Solomon, sir.
Bring it in under remote control.
Captain, the battle at Solomon
seems rather desperate.
Sir?
Ignore the escape rocket and...
I beg your pardon. But you don't
understand the feelings of soldiers in space.
I don't?
At times like this...
Soldiers can fight in space,
risking their own lives...
...because they believe their comrades
will come to rescue them.
If we don't hurry, they'll drift out of range.
All right. Bring it in.
Yes, sir!
Mineva...
That's an allied fleet.
We're saved.
I'm pleased with this thing's power.
But at this rate,
our base will be badly damaged.
Control room!
Yes, Your Excellency.
How many vessels do we have left?
The enemy's new weapon and mobile suits...
...have destroyed or immobilized
three-quarters of our vessels.
All right! Tell the rest to charge
straight through the enemy's main fleet!
Sir?!
And I'll lead the remaining Rick Doms
and Zakus out of Solomon!
Sir! Good luck, Your Excellency!
Thanks, and the same to you.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
Sir, we've confirmed
enemy fleet leaving Granada.
We can hold on a little longer, correct?
Yes!
But the remaining enemy vessels have
launched from the other side of Solomon.
Can we get them with
what's left of the Solar System?
We'd have a 60 percent chance of success.
Let's give it a try.
Focal coordinates, 0-6-3-5!
Making minor adjustments to the Y-axis!
0-0-4! 0-0-2!
All fleets will finish off the enemy
after we focus the Solar System!
Full speed ahead!
Forget the ships we passed.
Others are ahead! Hit whatever you can!
Next...?
Damn, I'm good!
Uh-oh!
I'm too late!
What kind of machine
could destroy mobile suits like this?
There!
What was that?
What's that?!
Another vessel leaving Solomon!
Receiving Solar System's
coded focusing signal!
What's that?!
The Solar System's still alive?!
Remaining ships will charge
the enemy's main force!
Good.
What's the Big Zam's target?!
The command vessel that's in the rear!
Ignore the small fry!
Sayla's craft has been hit!
We'll take her in through Deck 3!
Do it quickly!
Once she's inside, we'll pursue the large
mobile armor that launched from Solomon.
Mirai?!
I'm sorry for the trouble, Lieutenant.
I'm better now.
All right. Vammas,
please return to the sub-bridge.
Yes, sir!
Bring the White Base around
180 degrees, Mirai! Hurry!
Yes, sir!
Salamis ships!
No problem! Fire forward beam!
I knew it!
That mobile armor isn't just big!
I just saw that thing deflect the beams!
Which means only missiles will work.
If we don't do something,
we'll just have more casualties!
The Big Zam will charge the main fleet.
But first give a flare to signal
that all units are to escape!
But sir...!
Our forces have been battered too much.
We are going to abandon Solomon.
Switch control over to my panel.
And you men must escape as well.
But... Your Excellency?!
Don't waste your lives!
We've got Doms and Zakus.
They can pull you off the battlefield!
Uh, yes, sir.
Now! Send out the flare signal!
I'm taking over the Big Zam!
I never expected Solomon
to fall so easily.
It's the Gundam!
I just can't fire on unarmed men.
Don't underestimate the Big Zam!
Those long-range beams have no effect!
I'll take as many of you as I can
with me to hell.
The large mobile suit is emitting
a powerful magnetic field.
Missiles! Intercept with missiles!
It's way too strong.
See?!
Once the Big Zam is mass-produced
we'll put an end to the Federation in no time!
Lieutenant Sleggar?!
You want us to dock...
and charge into them in G-Armor mode?!
Let's do it, Chief Amuro!
R-Right! But Lieutenant, what's your plan?
Don't talk to me about plans!
With their magnetic field, all we can do
is get in close and try our beam weapons!
Gotcha!
If these beam cannons fall...
...use the Gundam's beam rifle,
then the beam saber.
With three levels of weaponry on our side,
even if we get shot down...
Lieutenant Sleggar!
Forget personal feelings.
I won't let it create any more casualties.
It sounds sad. But this is a war.
Amuro! We'll attack from below!
From below?! Anti-air defenses!
Not over yet!!
Damn them!
Lieutenant!
They got him!
You...!
Is a single mobile suit...
...going to defeat the Big Zam?!
No! I won't be defeated!
I won't let a punk like you beat me!
I won't be defeated!
For the glory of Zeon!
For my own pride!
You will not defeat me!
Who is he?
What is that?
Solomon has fallen...?
Yes, sir.
How's this? Captain, you'll take Lady Zenna
to Granada aboard this Gwazine.
I'll board a Chivvay so that I can
keep an eye on the Federation's next move.
Right. We've missed our chance
to stage a surprise attack, after all.
That's true.
Your role as strategist depended on
Solomon holding out until we arrived.
I'll leave a few vessels to collect intelligence
and rescue the men.
Very well. I'll help with that, too.
Tell me it's a lie.
You can't tell me it's a lie, can you, Amuro?
I'll spread my wings and wait for you
tsubasa wo hirogete anata wo matsuwa
I wonder if you're suffering today
kyou no anata wa tsuraino kashira
We do not feel such things
sonna koto nai watashitachi
So please sleep now, Amuro
dakara ne oyasumi Amuro
People say our times are awful
konna jidai to hito wa iu
If this warmth is real for certain
kono nukumori ga tashika nara tashika nara
You'll be able to find it
mitsukaruyo
A dream, it is a dream, a dream
yume sore wa yume yume
Char prepares himself for the next battle.
Unaware, Amuro and M'Quve fight a
mortal combat in an uninhabited wasteland.
As she observes the battle, young Lalah
has visions of her destiny calling for her.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
The Duel in Texas.
Next Time
The Duel in Texas
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...